DAVID DAYAN-ROSENMAN, MD, MS

19 Verndale St, Unit 1, Brookline, MA 02446 +1 (917) 547-9011 – david@dayan-rosenman.net www.periscopeclinicalanalytics.com



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced physician leader with a specialization in addiction medicine, HIV care, population health management, and integrated care design. Expert in leveraging multimodal analytics to optimize healthcare delivery for socially complex populations. Demonstrated success in leading clinical program development that cohesively integrates medical, behavioral, and substance use care to enhance patient outcomes and care efficiency

EDUCATION & POST-GRADUATE TRAINING

Addiction Medicine Fellowship The Addiction Institute of New York Mount Sinai Roosevelt Hospital, New York, NY	7/2014-6/2015
Internal Medicine Residency Residency Program in Primary Care and Social Internal Medicine Montefiore Medical Center - Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, NY	7/2011-6/2014
Psychiatry Internship Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences Montefiore Medical Center - Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, NY	7/2010-6/2011
Doctor of Medicine Weill Cornell Medical College, New York, NY	6/2010
Master of Arts, Political Science University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA	12/2005
Master of Science, Theoretical Computer Science and Algorithms Université Paris 7/Ecole Normale Supérieure/Ecole Polytechnique, Paris, France	6/2001
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Magna Cum Laude Université Paris 7, Paris, France	6/2000

BOARDS, CERTIFICATIONS & LICENSURE

American Board of Preventive Medicine - Addiction Medicine Subspecialty	2017–Present
American Academy of HIV Medicine Specialist (AAHIVS)	2016-Present
American Board of Addiction Medicine	2015-Present
American Board of Internal Medicine	2014-Present
Unrestricted state medical licenses: MA, NY, NC, FL, IL, IN, OH	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal, Periscope Clinical Analytics LLC

A boutique consulting firm providing high-value expertise for population health management.

- Plan, design and implement clinical analytics foundational capabilities
- Build tooling for population health management
- Multimodal analytics including medical claims, clinical data and Electronic Health Record.
- Quality Improvement for medical, substance use and behavioral conditions.
- Collaboration with clinical and data infrastructure/engineering teams.

4/2024-Present

Cityblock Health

A value-based, tech-enabled health start-up providing integrated medical, behavioral and substance use care to socially complex medicaid- and dual medicaid-medicare members

Clinical Analytics Consultant | 5/2024-7/2024

Implement clinical analytics program that was designed and piloted in previous position

- Rapid Implementation using claims data, AthenaOne EHR data, and external lab data
- Use of BigQuery, SQL, Looker, and Google Workspace Connected Sheets
- Support Clinical Informatics team

Head of Primary Care Program Design | 7/2023-4/2024

Contribute to expanded primary care strategy along with VP for integrated care, including buy vs. build decisions and value-based partnership with external vendors

- Design integrated care programs/pathways for delivery of specialty care in primary care
- Pilot clinical analytics for population health management and QI
- Provide subject matter expertise for Substance Use, HIV, Gender Affirmation, and Kidney Care
- Clinically supervise and mentor advanced practice providers and social workers

Medical Director, Integrated Care Design for Behavioral Health & Substance Use | 1/2023-7/2023 Design training, chose protocols, build EHR tools and templates, and provide mentorship to upskill primary care provider in treatment of anxiety, depression, alcohol and opioid use disorders

- Implement collaborative care management and advanced behavioral health programs
- Implement Contingency management for the treatment of stimulants, opioids, and alcohol
- Integrate Harm Reduction services

Contracted Physician | 4/2020-8/2020

Participate in COVID-19 response and in clinical projects

- COVID testing and care
- Clinical supervision of nurse home visiting program
- Initial implementation of population-based program for Chronic & End-Stage Kidney Disease

Per-diem Physician, Callen-Lorde Community Health Center, New York, NY

3/2022-Present

Callen-Lorde is a global leader in LGBTQ+ healthcare. It provides sensitive, quality health care and related services targeted to New York's LGBTQ+ communities

- Urgent care and longitudinal follow-up for LGBTQ-identified patients
- Gender Affirmation, HIV primary care, HIV prevention, Sexual Health

Per-diem Physician, The Reach Medical Project, Ithaca, NY

3/2022-11/2023

The REACH Project owns and operates the first low threshold, harm reduction medical practice in Ithaca, NY. It offers Medication-Assisted Therapy (MAT), Hep C treatment, primary care, and behavioral services in a stigma-free, inclusive setting.

- Treatment for patients with substance use disorders
- Including Buprenorphine ("Suboxone"), and Harm reduction interventions

Clinician educator, Woodhull Medical Center, Brooklyn, NY

3/2020-2/2022

- Volunteer inpatient teaching medicine attending at New York City Health+Hospital during the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Ambulatory clinic preceptor (part-time) for the Internal Medicine residency program, lead for the LGBTQ primary care track.

Principal, Addiction Consult NYC

11/2019-8/2020

- Enable organizations to integrate substance use care into primary care.
- Provide clinical informatics expertise including design of EHR tools and population health reporting tools to measure impact of interventions.
- Clients included Cityblock and Brownsville Multi-Service Family Health Center

Medical Director, New York Hotel Trades Council and Hotel Association of NYC, Inc. Employee Benefit Funds, Brooklyn, NY

8/2019-11/2019

- Manage medical teams including primary care and specialty providers
- Lead process improvement

David Dayan-Rosenman, MD, MS | Periscope Clinical Analytics Medical Director, Housing Works East New York Health Center, Brooklyn, NY 7/2017-7/2019 Oversee delivery of clinical services at a Federally Qualified Health Center Supervise Quality Improvement meeting for Ryan-White-funded HIV program Increased clinic viral load suppression rate from 78% to 90% using population-health tools to manage intensive case management Develop multidisciplinary services for patients of transgender experience Design and implement clinical care flow for same-day access to Medication Assisted Treatment with Buprenorphine and for same day access to PrEP. Conduct forensic examinations and write affidavits for asylum seekers Primary Care Physician, Montefiore South Bronx Health Center Bronx, NY 10/2015-6/2017 • Coordinator for Montefiore Ryan-White HIV program • Established Medication Assisted Treatment Program for Opioid Use Disorder Collaborate with St Ann's Corner syringe exchange program • Contributed to Transgender Health Working Group Fellow Physician, Mount Sinai Roosevelt Hospital, New York, NY 7/2014-6/2015 • Inpatient Drug Detoxification and Rehabilitation Opioid Treatment Program - including screening and linkage to HCV care Established Opioid Overdose Prevention Program (OOPP) Resident Physician, Montefiore Medical Center, Bronx, NY 7/2011-6/2014 Participation in multiple electives The Bronx Human Rights Clinic | Health Right International Transition Clinic for recently incarcerated patients Reproductive Health Elective, Planned Parenthood, Denver, CO Global Health Elective, Ministry of Health District Hospital, Kisoro, Uganda Resident Physician, Psychiatry Service - Montefiore Medical Center, Bronx, NY 7/2010-6/2011 • Evaluation and management in the Psychiatric Emergency Room • Inpatient psychiatry unit for decompensated patients ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS Clinical Assistant Professor of Medicine, SUNY Downstate, Brooklyn, NY 10/2018-8/2019 Precept Medical Students during their primary care clerkship Introduce students to the care of vulnerable populations, including substance users, people experiencing homelessness, people living with HIV, and transgender and gender-non-binary persons Assistant Professor of Medicine, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, NY 7/2016-6/2017

Precept Medical Students during their primary care clerkship

PUBLICATIONS

- Dayan-Rosenman, David, and Spencer, Steven. "Implementation of Medications for Alcohol and Opioid Use Disorders in a Value-Based Organization - Unlocking Value by Addressing Unmet Needs for Medicaid and Dually-Eligible Beneficiaries." Population Health Management [forthcoming - accepted 5/2024]
- Avin, Chen, and <u>Dayan-Rosenman</u>, <u>David</u>. "Evolutionary reputation games on social networks." Complex Systems 17.3 (2007): 259-278. (link)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

• Fluent in English, French and Spanish.